WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
The Harfoots, where are they?
I was hoping to find my friends.
Well, there's what you're searchin' for
and there's what you find, now,
isn't there?
This... magic.
Might you teach me how to wield a staff?
It's yours to wield already,
if you prove yourself worthy of it.
Valandil tells me
that in the Old Quarter,
prayers ascend night and day for you.
It was you, who opened my heart again
to the way of The Faithful.
But together we can fight.
Not every battle
must be fought to be won.
Inform the jailer he was the one
who started the uprising.
Stone-singers speak
of hearing the mountain.
With this Ring, I can see it.
We have barely taken a thimble
from the ocean of her riches.
He's changed.
Greed is not his way. It never has been.
Is it possible the Ring he's wearing...
No. There simply cannot be
a fault in your Rings.
Then maybe,
the fault's in the Ring-maker.
How much do you really know
about this Annatar?
Did you alter the Dwarven Rings,
yes or no?
No.
We did.
We must atone for our mistakes
by completing the Rings together.
The Nine must redeem the Seven.
They must redeem us all.
The Orcs are not in Mordor.
A legion of them are headed for Eregion.
Galadriel was right. You must send
the army to Eregion this moment!
I brought you here
not as a prisoner...
but as a potential ally.
For we share a common enemy.
- Synced and corrected by synk -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -
You shut up.
They'll call us deserters.
I don't care what they call us.
Anything's better than dying
to help Adar chase a ghost.
Ye Rings of Men, why do you still defy me?
You, who live not, breathe not,
possess not mind nor will?
What pride is woven in your inmost self,
that you resist my hand?
Again.
More silver.
More mithril.
There is no more mithril.
The Dwarves have been tardy
with their delivery.
So chase them down.
We have tried, my lord.
All our dispatches go unanswered.
Must I do everything myself?
We are laboring as hard as we can.
Some of us have noticed you seem...
especially ill-tempered of late, my lord.
What is your name again, smith?
You mean, you don't remember?
Of course I remember.
Just, just... give me a moment.
- Lord Celebrimbor.
- Give me a moment, I said!
Everyone take a respite.
Mirdania. She's called Mirdania.
You cannot be expected
to remember everything.
No, just, it's simple things, even.
Earlier, I could've sworn I left
my creasing hammer just here, and...
You mean that hammer?
Yes.
My mind must be going.
Or you are going so deep into it,
coming out again
has become an incredible burden.
- Yeah.
- So deep.
I imagine at times you must be tempted
simply to stay there awhile,
gain some clarity.
Hmm.
I am well.
I'm just fatigued.
Then I am afraid
you will not like the tidings I bring.
Your people demand an audience.
No, no.
You are the Lord of Eregion.
You have responsibilities.
Yes, and my greatest responsibility
is to the Rings.
Until the Nine are complete,
nothing else matters.
Very well, then.
As you wish.
Oh, there is something more.
The Dwarves are late with our mithril.
Could you see to it?
At once.
The Greatest of Elven-smiths
is consumed by his work.
He asks that I handle all matters
of administration in his stead.
Now, what seems to be at issue?
Show him.
Show me what?
This gatehouse is typically athrum
with artisans and merchants
traveling into the city.
But it all strangely halted yester-eve.
We sent a search party across the river
to see if there was an obstruction
upon the road.
But only one soldier returned.
Where is he?
Washed up this morning.
He appeared to be carrying a message.
Bury him.
Show this to no one.
And shall I inform Lord Celebrimbor?
No.
He has asked me to see to it
that no one is permitted to disturb him.
Not even the smiths.
He has stripped us of our duties?
Yes, I am afraid so.
Was it that business
about him forgetting my name?
I know I was brusque with him, but...
He's not himself, Mirdania.
For now, all we can do
is leave him in solitude.
Give him time. And pray.
Pray that he finishes this work
before it finishes him.
Can I trust you...
to make sure
the others respect his wishes as well?
Of course, my lord.
My lord, the carving. On the body.
What did it say?
"Where is He?"
During my brief time in your capture,
you seemed intent on finding Sauron.
One might even say, consumed by it,
the way one always is,
once he has wormed his way
inside your mind.
You know nothing of my mind.
You yielded to him.
I resisted.
For a while, perhaps.
But sooner or later, he sees you.
Not just who you are,
but who you wish to be.
His eye bores a hole
and the rest of him slithers in.
For a while, he even makes you believe
that his power has become yours.
Irresistible power...
that makes every desire's fulfillment
seem inevitable.
An ocean of color
against which everything else
feels forever thereafter...
A dull gray.
What did he promise you?
An army.
Do you want to know what he offered me?
I care not.
Children.
Then it would seem he gave us both
what we desired.
You see,
it is not his lies
which must be extinguished.
It is him.
And I can help you do it.
I can help you destroy Sauron.
What help could you possibly provide, Orc?
Uruk.
Morgoth's crown. I was told...
There are many stories of what happened,
after the Silmarils were pried
from its settings.
But I was there
when Sauron re-fired it to fit himself.
I was there when he kneeled to be crowned.
And I was the one
who used its power, to slay him.
If what you say is true,
why did he return?
Because I had not yet found you.
What part am I to play in this?
It is said the Three Elven Rings
saved your kind from fading.
Is it true?
If it is, then perhaps together,
this crown and your Rings
would be powerful enough
to truly destroy Sauron forever.
The Deceiver believes
he is still beyond my grasp.
But I know he hides in Eregion.
And I suspect you know for certain...
Halbrand is Sauron.
Isn't he?
The fate of that city
now rests on your ability
to put aside your pride.
I suggest you find the will to do so.
If you can.
We will speak again.
Outlawry.
Incitement of a violent conflagration
that led to loss of life.
And last, but most odious,
the crime of high treason.
Taken in sum, these hideous breaches
of law warrant a sentence of death.
Yes!
He doesn't deserve to be put to death.
Well, maybe.
However,
given his many years
of faithful service to our kingdom,
it is the judgment of this court
that the accused be set free.
Set free...
Set free, provided, of course,
he renounces his crimes
and pledges his loyalty
to Númenor's true ruler.
Elendil, son of Amandil,
do you renounce your crimes?
I do.
And do you accept Ar-Pharazôn
as Númenor's true King?
I do not.
Speak louder, Elendil,
so that the assembled
may hear you properly.
I do not!
For Númenor's true ruler is now,
until the end of her days,
Míriel, daughter of Tar-Palantír!
And the only traitor here is you!
Now what are we to do with him?
You have done quite enough, boy.
Perhaps we should let the Valar
decide his fate.
If The Faithful wish to live
by the old traditions,
they ought to die by them as well.
Nori.
Snorin'? Who's snorin'?
No one.
I... I saw something.
The Secret Fire whispers to us,
if we have ears to hear.
It tells us things. Even shows us things.
Does it show us things that will be?
Or things that only might be?
It shows tomorrow's clouds
as clear as yesterday's sunshine.
How do I learn to master its power?
To fight back against the darkness?
What does the Secret Fire need
with you as a master?
But if I cannot master it,
then how am I to use it?
Every trial that you have met thus far,
you have failed.
Fail the trial before you now,
and there will not be another.
Tell me what I must do.
Follow ol' Tom. For he will show you.
Why don't you just leave?
Get clear of 'em. Run away.
And where exactly would we go?
Why... anywhere you want.
Harfoots find a new place to live
every month.
Hmm.
This Smial, my mum and her folks
dug for me.
I was born in it.
I've been tendin' that tree
since I was big enough to balance a rake.
I married my Bramgar in its shadow.
And last spring, when he passed,
I buried him under it.
And one day, I'll be buried beside him.
Every one of these Smials
has a story like that.
You see, this place,
it's not just where we live.
It's our home.
It's me.
- Nori...
- No. I got you into this rut.
Maybe it's up to me to get you out.
Turn myself in now,
there's a chance I can get Poppy out, too.
Been meaning to ask ya,
why is it exactly they call you Nobody?
My folks aren't the most decisive.
Took 'em a long time
to settle on a name.
Well, how long?
Well, one or two years.
That's not so long.
One or two years ago.
And by that point, Nobody'd stuck.
Hmm.
Why are you lookin' at me like that?
I was gonna... I was thinkin' of askin',
what with all of us maybe
about to be murdered and all,
if you wanna go...
Quit talking.
- Merimac.
- Poppy.
Did you have lizard for supper?
Why do you ask?
She's right, Nor.
Those big folk are only after us
to get to him, the Stranger.
Turn yourself in, you might well be
puttin' the whole world at risk.
Not just Stoors, but Harfoots too.
Your ma and da. Dilly.
How many times you told me he's important?
Few more'n a rabbit's dozen, I suppose.
Thing is, Nor, sooner or later,
when you say somethin' enough,
I start believin' ya.
I say we fight for it.
The Dark Wizard found his staff.
And now, the time has come
for you to find yours.
Oh!
Which one is it?
You'll find your true staff
only when the vision of your heart
is single to the service
of the Secret Fire.
But there are so many.
One could spend months
searching out there.
You have all the time you need.
Unless, there is somewhere else
you wish to be.
I saw her. Nori.
She was...
Somehow, I know that
unless I find her soon, she will die.
Both of them will die.
Many that die deserve life.
Some that live deserve death.
Who are you to give it to them?
Once I know that she's safe,
I could return to you.
No. You cannot.
There are times when one path becomes two,
and you must choose.
Turn away now,
and you can never return to this path.
Is there no other way?
Sauron rises in the west.
A Dark Wizard in the east.
Every soul in Middle-earth is in peril.
Will you abandon them to their doom?
She is my friend.
Your friend or your destiny?
The choice is yours.
Come on, put your bread into it.
Sire.
You summoned me, Father?
No.
He did.
I see the Seven are serving you well,
Prince Durin.
They're serving someone well.
I'll give you that.
Circumstances have changed.
I have just learned that Eregion
is under threat of invasion.
Without mithril, the remaining
Rings of Power may never be complete.
We need more.
And we need it now.
How much shall I offer you?
There is nothing you could d...
How much of what?
I understand you're expanding
your mining operations.
We can provide a steady supply of timber
to help build platforms, mine shafts.
Or perhaps Khazad-dûm
would prefer something...
more precious?
Father, perhaps we'd be wise
to discuss this first in private?
There's nothing to discuss.
I've already decided.
And?
The answer is no.
Please give my regrets
to Lord Celebrimbor.
King Durin.
Prince. Farewell.
Thank Aulë.
For a moment, I was afraid
you'd taken leave of all your senses.
On the contrary.
I have never been of sounder mind.
But do not worry, my son.
They'll be back.
Back?
You heard him.
War is coming to Middle-earth.
And the army that bears
the weapons and armor of mithril
is all but invincible.
We can name our price.
Have you gone mad?
The whole world's gone mad, my son.
But it is to us to grip it by the throat.
Tell Narvi to double his work teams.
We're expanding the dig.
Father.
Take off the Ring.
I will not.
It is mine.
Belongs to me.
No.
You belong to it.
If it is otherwise, please, prove it.
Take it off.
I have nothing to prove to you, boy.
Then he's left us no choice.
We'll lay our bodies in front of that mine
ourselves if we have to.
He'd call the whole army down on us.
Let him!
If he's so in thrall to that Ring,
he'd turn his troops on his own son,
it'll show every Dwarf in Khazad-dûm
he's no longer fit to rule.
They'll take his crown.
How can you talk about him this way?
Durin.
You're talkin' about humiliatin' him.
About destroying him.
I love him as much as you do.
Aulë knows, he's twice the father to me
my own ever was.
But the Dwarf on that throne
is not your father.
As long as he's wearing that Ring,
he's deaf to all other
voices, even ours.
And every Dwarf
in this mountain's in peril!
Durin!
Durin?
Durin, are you...
I can't do it.
I can't do it, Disa.
I look at him, and in his eyes, I...
I still see my father.
Lost and far away, yes,
but he's still in there.
Always have you seen the light
at the end of the cave, my love.
Come.
If we don't act now, we'll never reach it.
He'll destroy himself
and take this kingdom with him.
At dawn, you are to be cast into the sea
to face Trial by Abyss.
They are summoning the sea-worm
as we speak.
I have spoken with Ar-Pharazôn.
He does not wish
to further antagonize The Faithful.
His offer of mercy still stands,
if you swear...
Swear fealty to him?
It is hardly mercy to ask a man
to set his integrity aflame.
After everything this family
has lost, I cannot lose you too.
Please, Father.
Please.
Swallow your pride.
If after all this, all you see is pride...
Then there are no words left
for us to speak.
The King said you'd say that.
Said your hatred for him
had become hatred for me,
and forever shut your ears to my voice.
So I knelt before him,
and I begged,
with my tongue to the dust,
for the chance to go to her.
I pray I wasn't wrong.
You do not belong in this place.
Bow to Pharazôn.
I command it.
If Númenor is to endure,
it needs men like you.
Men who will champion all
that is precious. Men of faith.
Faith is not faith if it is not lived.
And in my heart, I know
you are this kingdom's true heir.
I cannot deny that knowledge.
Were I to do so, I would cease
to be the man you wish to save.
What if you're wrong?
Then I would rather die
with a heart that is whole,
than live with one broken by cowardice.
What of my heart?
If it is the will of the Valar
that my life be spared...
then it will be.
What if it isn't?
"The sea is always right."
Step!
Disa?
Disa, we're here on orders from the king.
So, please move,
otherwise I've no choice
but to see you moved.
I'm sorry.
Was that meant to frighten us off?
No.
They are.
I love you.
Love me later.
This is only the beginning.
They'll be back.
And there'll be more of them.
Then, we'll be ready.
Do you forsake all earthly authority
and accept the judgment of the Valar?
I accept their judgment.
Throw him in.
Release him!
Given that his crime
was committed in my name,
I have the right to face
the Valar's judgment in his place.
- It should be him. Take him.
- No, no. No!
My Queen?
She's correct.
It's all in there. You must.
Is this true?
By the letter of the law, yes.
So it shall be.
No, take me.
Take me.
Míriel, you can't... You cannot...
If we are to walk the path
of The Faithful,
it must be me who takes the first step.
- It's here! Look!
- Over the horizon.
Yeah, it's coming now.
The Valar have deemed her...
- There she is!
- Innocent!
My Queen!
Hail Tar-Míriel,
Queen of the Sea!
- Hail Queen Míriel.
- Hail Queen of the Sea.
Hail Queen Míriel.
Yes. Halbrand is Sauron.
He's in Eregion to craft Rings
that will allow him to dominate my kind.
- And yours.
- Every kind in Middle-earth.
But he will not attempt escape
until his task is complete.
And that gives us a momentary advantage.
Us?
Unlock me.
As we speak, Elrond hastens from Lindon
with an army of Elves.
And Nenya, my Ring.
I see.
Once he arrives,
he will seal off the city,
loose Celebrimbor from Sauron's grasp,
and then together,
Uruk,
you and I will eradicate
all trace of Sauron from this world.
Never to return.
And what then?
Any Rings that have known his touch
must be destroyed.
I meant, what then for the Uruk?
Will your High King permit us
to return home in peace?
Or will he proceed with his plans
to invade Mordor?
The shadow has not only overcome you,
it has overcome all Elvendom.
In the end,
your drive to prove your virtue will work
right into Sauron's designs.
You speak lies.
Hoping I will reveal something.
You have already revealed
everything I hoped you would and more.
All right, all right.
It is time!
All of Eregion may well be
under Sauron's control by now.
It will take far more than a legion
of your children to lay siege to it.
Did you really think I would attempt
to challenge the might of Sauron
with a single legion?
Now that you have confirmed
beyond any doubt who he is,
and told me who carries your Ring,
Eregion will fall.
And Sauron with it.
No.
This must be what he wants.
Sauron has no army of his own,
so he's lured yours here instead.
He wants you to attack Eregion.
Bind her. She will be useful later.
- I beg you. Do not be a fool.
- Get down here.
Do not do this. Do not take his lure.
I will make him choke on it.
No!
You mustn't. This is all his design!
This is what Sauron wants!
This is what he wants!
This way. Come on.
Push! Move!
Harder!
Sound the bells.
We're under attack!
Shut the gates!
Raise the drawbridge!
How fares your progress?
Did you not hear that?
Outside. Sounded like a siege alarm.
I assure you, I have the affairs
of the city well in hand.
I shall decide that for myself.
You belong in here, my friend.
I've had quite enough
of you telling me where I belong!
Unhand me, friend.
Leave this tower now,
and when the Men of Middle-earth fall,
I swear to you,
every soul in the seen or unseen world
will know that it was you
who was the architect of their demise.
We still have nine Rings to forge!
- Sure.
- It's a horse.
For centuries,
I sought to craft objects of great power.
But I failed.
The truth of it is,
I came to Eregion
not because the Valar needed you,
but because I did.
I...
I cannot forge more Rings.
And without mithril, I...
Be at ease.
I have been to Khazad-dûm.
Mithril ore.
Refined to a powder by Narvi himself.
From the purest deposit yet found
in their mines.
One-ninth portion per Ring.
It should be enough.
We are close, now, Celebrimbor.
So close to achieving
what we set out to do.
I give you my oath,
upon my immortal being,
when the history of this Age is written,
the Silmarils,
well...
They will merit little more
than a whisper.
But your Rings,
the Rings of Power,
they will be deemed the most
precious creations in all Middle-earth.
Yeah.
Do not turn back now, at the very moment
your boots are kissing the threshold.
Use it, my friend.
Best Fëanor.
Best yourself.
One last time.
I've written a poem
but I fear your beauty
still overshadows
anything I could possible write.
Come, children!
Yeah!
Release!
- Synced and corrected by synk -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -